（銃声）
（藍原(あいはら)延珠(えんじゅ)）ああ… 蓮太郎(れんたろう)
Rentaro...
We're going, too.
（里見(さとみ)蓮太郎）俺たちも行くぜ！
I will stay behind.
（千寿(せんじゅ)夏世(かよ)）私は残ります
If someone doesn't hold them back here,
ここで 誰かが食い止めないと―
win or lose, we'll all die.
勝っても負けても全滅しますよ
Don't worry. If I'm at a disadvantage, I will run.
安心してください
劣勢になったら 逃げますので
Please take care of Shogen-san.
将監(しょうげん)さんをお願いします
分かった
All right. Let's go, Enju.
行くぞ 延珠！
（延珠）うん
Yeah.
♪～
～♪
#04 Black Bullet
It's so quiet...
静かだな
Yeah.
ああ
（延珠）うわっ… ん？
What is this?
なんだ？ これは…
ひぃっ
（物音）
Sword...
（伊熊(いくま)将監）剣は… 俺の剣は…
My sword...
Ikuma Shogen?
伊熊… 将監か
Have you... seen my sword?
（将監）俺の剣を知らねえか？
As long as... I have that...
あれが あれば…
I can... still... fight...
まだ… 戦え…
る… ううっ
（延珠）あっ
Papa, I'm surprised!
（蛭子(ひるこ)小比奈(こひな)）パパ ビックリ！
（２人）あっ
He really is still alive.
（小比奈）ホントに生きてたよ
The end is near.
（蛭子影胤(かげたね)）幕が近い
Let us finish this, Satomi-kun.
決着をつけよう 里見くん
（防衛大臣）付近の民警は―
With the civil officers we have
in the vicinity, it'd take even
一番近くにいるペアでも
１時間以上かかります
the closest pair at least an hour.
（ドアが開く音）
（聖天子(せいてんし)）あ…
Kisara.
（天童菊之丞(てんどうきくのじょう)）木更(きさら)
I called for her.
私(わたくし)がお呼びしました
President Tendo, what would you say is the
天童社長
里見ペアの勝率は
いかほどと見ますか？
success rate for the Satomi pair?
If I may voice my own expectation,
（天童木更）
私の期待を加味してよいなら
they will win.
勝ちます 絶対に！
No matter what.
What? They're up against the survivor
of the New Humanity Creation Plan!
（自衛官）はあ!?
相手は 新人類創造計画の
生き残りなんだぞ
勝ち目なんか…
They don't stand a...
10年前…
Ten years ago,
Gastrea came into my house
and devoured my parents.
私の家に ガストレアが侵入して
父と母を食い殺しました
Because of the stress I endured at the time,
私は そのときのストレスで―
my kidneys are barely functioning.
腎臓の機能が ほぼ停止しています
そのとき 里見蓮太郎は
私をかばって
At that time, Satomi Rentaro protected me,
and the Gastrea took his right hand,
right leg, and left eye.
右手 右足 左目を
ガストレアに奪われました
On the verge of death,
he was taken to Section 22.
ひん死の彼が運び込まれたのは
セクション22
執刀医は 室戸(むろと) 菫(すみれ)医師
The performing surgeon was Dr. Muroto Sumire.
Muroto Sumire?
室戸 菫…
あっ ま… まさか！
I-It can't be!
You will not retrieve the case.
（影胤）
君は ケースを取り戻せない
Because...
なぜなら…
We stand in your way!
私たちが
立ちはだかっているからだ！
A second defeat,
the annihilation of my comrades...
２度の敗北
味方の全滅
Sure! I couldn't have asked for
a better situation, damn it!
ああ…
願ってもない状況だ クソ野郎！
I will eliminate you!
貴様を排除する！
（影胤）フフッ…
（指を鳴らす音）
Tendo Martial Arts First Style, Number 3:
天童式戦闘術 一の型三番！
轆轤鹿伏鬼(ろくろかぶと)
Rokuro Kabuto!
（影胤）ハハハハ…
（蓮太郎）くっ うう…
（影胤）ん？
（蓮太郎）うおおー！
（影胤）うわっ
He broke through Maximum Pain?
マキシマムペインを破った!?
あ…
Artificial limbs made from Varanium?
バラニウムの義肢だと!?
Could it be that you're also...
まさか 君も!?
I'll introduce myself, as well, Kagetane.
（蓮太郎）俺も名乗るぞ 影胤
元陸上自衛隊東部方面隊
I am formerly from the Ground
Self-Defense Force's Eastern Force,
787th Mechanization Special Unit,
of the New Humanity Creation Plan...
７８７機械化特殊部隊
新人類創造計画
Satomi Rentaro!
里見蓮太郎！
There was another one?
（自衛官）もう１人いたのか？
Another of the human weapons
born of the Gastrea War?
ガストレア戦争が生んだ
人間兵器が…
（影胤）クッ… フフッ
ハハハハ… うっ！
私は痛い
I am in pain...
I am alive.
私は生きてる
すばらしきかな人生！
What a magnificent life!
Hallelujah!
ハレルヤ！
Don't be mean to Papa!
パパをいじめるなー！
（延珠）うおー！
（影胤）フフフフ…
Cry, Sodomy.
哭(な)け ソドミー
唄え ゴスペル
Sing, Gospel.
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
We were created to kill.
（影胤）
我々は 殺すために作られた
If the Gastrea War were to recommence,
ガストレア戦争が再開すれば―
the significance of our lives will be proven.
我々の存在意義が証明される
Are you trying to tell me...
that's the reason you're...
（蓮太郎）まさか 貴様
そのためだけに！
What did the people around you think
（影胤）君のイニシエーターが―
when they found out your Initiator
was one of the Cursed Children?
呪われた子供たちだと
露見したときの―
周りの反応は どうだった？
祝福されたか？
Did they offer their blessings?
Were you touched by endless cheers of joy?
鳴りやまぬ歓声に
心を洗われたか？
The world that we wish for
is different from theirs.
彼らと我々が望む世界は
違うのだよ！
We have been chosen.
我々は選ばれた者だ
さあ 里見蓮太郎
私と共に来い！
Now, Satomi Rentaro.
Come with me!
ざけんじゃねえよ クソ野郎！
You've got to be kidding me, you bastard.
There's no way in hell
貴様の語る未来
I can accept the future you're talking about!
断じて 許容できねえ！
（延珠）とりゃー！
うわっ
（影胤）フハハ…
（蓮太郎）延珠！
Enju!
うっ
If you cannot abide...
（影胤）従えないのなら―
Then die!
死ねー！
うわっ…
（延珠）うっ…
（蓮太郎）ぐっ…
（延珠）あっ
ああ…
You have lost.
（影胤）君の 負けだ
Am I... going to die?
（蓮太郎）俺は―
死ぬのか？
うっ… 延珠…
Enju...
Rentaro! Please do not leave me alone!
蓮太郎！
妾(わらわ)を１人にしないでくれー！
はっ…
くっ くぅ…
The AGV experimental drug was
created from the Gastrea virus.
（室戸 菫）ＡＧＶ試験薬は―
ガストレアウイルスによって
生成された
It gives humans the regenerative
abilities of the Gastrea,
ガストレア並みの再生能力を
人間に与えるが―
but there is a 20% chance that they
will turn into Gastrea themselves.
20％もの確率で
ガストレア化させてしまう
If you can avoid it, don't use them.
できれば 使うなよ
ううっ うっ！
うわっ…
うっ ぐっ…
うっ うっ… うわー！
（蓮太郎のうめき声）
（影胤）ん？
R-Rentaro...
れ… 蓮太郎!?
（蓮太郎）うっ！
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
はっ…
I won... that gamble.
賭けに勝ったぞ
Satomi-kun, you're...
（影胤）里見くん 君は…
Tendo Martial Arts Suiten Ippeki Stance:
天童式戦闘術 水天一碧(すいてんいっぺき)の構え
（小比奈）うっ！
あっ
雲嶺毘湖鯉鮒(うねびこりゅう)
Unebiko Ryu!
（影胤）あっ ああっ…
ああっ ああっ…
Inzen Kokutei!
隠禅(いんぜん)･哭汀(こくてい)
Am I... going to...
（影胤）私は… 君に…
lose to you?
負けるのか…
Papa... Papa...
パパ…
Hiruko Kagetane's signal has disappeared!
（オペレーター）
蛭子影胤の反応 消失！
（一同の歓声）
（聖天子）フゥ…
（警告音）
あ…
ああっ…
蓮太郎！
Rentaro!
It's all right now.
もう 大丈夫だ
Papa!
パパー！
No... No, Papa!
イヤよ…
イヤよ パパー！ ああ…
Papa...
パパ…
（泣き声）
She's no longer an enemy.
彼女はもう 敵じゃない
（携帯電話の着信音）
（蓮太郎）ん？
（延珠）あっ
（携帯電話の着信音）
I won like I promised, Kisara-san.
約束どおり勝ったぜ 木更さん
Yeah, I saw.
（木更）うん 見たわ
But, Satomi-kun...
でもね 里見くん
I've got some bad news I have to tell you.
悪いニュースを
伝えなきゃならない
A Stage Five Gastrea
ステージⅤのガストレアが―
has shown itself.
姿を現したの！
（スコーピオンの雄たけび）
（雄たけび）
Is everything over?
全部… 終わりなのか？
We won't let it end!
（木更）まだ 終わらせない！
Seitenshi-sama has given her consent to my plan.
私の作戦 聖天子様から
お許しを頂いたわ
The answer is to the southeast of your position.
答えは 君から見て
南東方向にある
Heaven's Ladder?
（蓮太郎）天(あま)の梯子(はしご)…
You're going to do it, Satomi-kun.
（木更）君がやるのよ 里見くん
（延珠･蓮太郎）ハァ ハァ ハァ…
The Linear Electromagnetic Projectile Device.
（木更）線形超電磁投射装置
Also known as Heaven's Ladder.
またの名を 天の梯子
A railgun module that fires metallic projectiles
直径800ミリ以下の
金属飛翔体を―
with a diameter less than
800 millimeters at near light speed.
亜光速まで加速して撃ち出す
レールガンモジュール
If we shoot Varanium rounds at a speed
回避不可能なスピードで
バラニウムの弾丸を撃ち込めば―
that would make regeneration impossible,
we'd be able to exterminate
even a Stage Five Gastrea.
ステージⅤガストレアだろうと
必ず消滅させることができるわ！
Commencing operation of the
Linear Electromagnetic Projectile Device.
（合成音声）
線形超電磁投射装置の
起動を開始します
Power supply, nominal.
電力供給 異常なし
Dewar vessels for liquid
helium storage, also nominal.
液体ヘリウム保存用の
デュワー瓶も異常なし
Thank you, Satomi-kun.
ありがとう 里見くん
We'll take care of the launch sequence here
起動後の発射シークエンスは
全て こちらで行うわ
as soon as everything is operational.
So all we have to do now is watch?
あとは 見ているだけでいいのか？
We couldn't do anything,
even if they told us to.
やれって言われても できねえよ
That's a Stage Five?
あれが ステージⅤなのか？
Yeah. The Zodiac Gastrea: Scorpion.
ああ
ゾディアックガストレア･
スコーピオン
It's the Gastrea that almost
destroyed the world.
かつて 世界を破滅寸前に
追い込んだ ガストレアだ
We've got trouble, Satomi-kun.
まずいわ 里見くん！
It's displaying a message saying
there's a problem in the chamber.
チャンバー部に
異常を伝える表示が出てる！
What does that mean?!
どういうことだよ！
It's possible the Varanium
rounds haven't been loaded.
（木更）もしかしたら
バラニウム徹甲弾が―
装填されてないかもしれない！
What?!
なんだって!?
（警告音）
Damn it! There aren't any rounds!
クソッ 弾がない！
Electrical power preservation system
coolant leak confirmed.
（合成音声）電力貯蔵システム
冷却流出を確認
Please halt the experiment at once.
速やかに 実験を停止してください
（延珠）
どうする 蓮太郎！
What do we do, Rentaro?
Because of the magnetic field...
（木更）磁場の影響で―
Satomi-kun, it's not responding
to remote commands.
里見くん…
遠隔入力を受けつけないの！
Satomi-kun...
里見くん！
ううっ…
Rentaro, you aren't going to...
蓮太郎 まさか お主…
うっ ううっ…
うおお…
うああ！
I'm going to use my right arm as a shell.
俺の右手を弾丸に使う
超バラニウムなら
問題ないはずだ！
There shouldn't be an issue
if it's super Varanium.
Varanium charge detected.
（合成音声）
バラニウム 装填を確認
We can't regain control
of the launch sequence!
射撃管制 復帰できません！
Without doing it manually on-site,
launch is impossible.
管制室からの手動射撃以外
不可能です！
Satomi-kun, did you hear that?
里見くん 聞こえた？
We can't fire the railgun from here.
こちらから
レールガンは撃てないの
Please! You have to do it!
お願い 君がやって！
あ… ちょっと 冗談だろ！
木更さん
Hey, you've got to be kidding!
There's no way I can do it!
俺には無理だって！ 木更さん！
Kisara-san!
Satomi-kun, the world— Please—
（木更）里見くん
世界を… お願い…
（無線が切れる音）
あ…
Kisara-san! Kisara-san!
木更さん… 木更さん！
Energy levels at 100%.
（合成音声）
エネルギー充填 100％
Initiating manual trigger system.
手動トリガーシステムを
起動します
あ…
Rentaro...
蓮太郎…
あ…
So I have to manually hit a
target 50 kilometers away?
距離50キロの目標に
手動で当てんのか…
Satomi-kun...
里見くん…
Satomi-san...
里見さん…
（雄たけび）
ぐっ…
I can't. I can't do it...
ダメだ
やれない… 俺には…
I...
Rentaro, I am here.
蓮太郎 妾がいる
は… 外したら 俺たちは終わりだ
If we miss, we're finished.
Of course we'll hit it.
（延珠）当たるに決まってる
The shell could veer toward the Tokyo Area
and cause an unprecedented disaster!
弾丸が東京エリアにそれて
未曽有の大災厄を
もたらすかもしれない
But if it's you, Rentaro,
it'll hit the target.
でも 蓮太郎なら当てる
Enju...
延珠…
You're the only one who can save the world.
（延珠）
蓮太郎だけが 世界を救える
No one else but you, Rentaro...
ほかの誰でもない 蓮太郎だけが…
（深呼吸）
Enju...
延珠 お前を絶対
失いたくない
I don't want to lose you, no matter what...
May I interpret that as a proposal?
今のは プロポーズ的な
解釈でいいのか？
You idiot.
アホか 家族的な解釈をしろ
Take it as me saying you're family!
A ten-year-old shouldn't be talking about love!
10歳のガキが
愛を語るんじゃねえよ
You're not scared anymore, right?
もう 怖くはないな？
（蓮太郎）フッ…
Yeah... Let's finish this!
ああ 終わりにするぞ
Enju...
（蓮太郎）延珠…
（延珠）ああ
Yeah.
Go!
（２人）いけー！
（蓮太郎）うっ くっ…
（スコーピオンの悲鳴）
あ…
Why didn't you run?
どうして 逃げなかった？
So you've... found me.
（夏世）見つかっちゃいました…
You said you'd run if you
were at a disadvantage.
（蓮太郎）
劣勢になったら逃げるって
言ってたじゃないか
Satomi-san, how's Shogen-san?
里見さん 将監さんは？
He's safe.
無事だ
はっ…
Satomi-san... I...
（夏世）里見さん 私は…
Yeah... There's no doubt.
（蓮太郎）ああ 間違いなく
侵食率が50％を超えている
The corrosion rate in your body is over 50%.
Please let me die as a human...
人のまま 私も死なせてください
私の存在を肯定してくれた
あなたを―
As the one who acknowledged my existence,
I didn't want to let you die.
死なせたくなかった
So I tried hard...
だから 頑張った
It was hard, but...
つらかったけど―
I'm glad I lived.
私 生きててよかった…
Right now, my heart
私の胸は 今…
is filled with gratitude...
感謝でいっぱいです
Thank you.
ありがとう
Hey, Satomi-san, you don't have
very many friends, do you?
ねえ 里見さんって
あんまり友達いないでしょ？
（蓮太郎）えっ？
I'll be your friend.
私が友達になってあげます
Yeah...
ああ… ありがとう
Thanks.
You are my irreplaceable friend.
お前は 俺の
かけがえのない友達だ
Satomi-san, from here on out...
（夏世）里見さん
これから先 暗闇で迷ったら―
If you get lost in the darkness,
follow the compass within your heart
心の中のコンパスに従って
and go towards the light...
光の方に…
Please save
この世界を…
this world...
救って…
（蓮太郎）うう…
（銃声）
（ヘリのローター音）
About the information leaked to Kagetane...
（蓮太郎）
影胤に情報がリークされた件
They're saying it was caused by Defense
Minister Kutsuoda's party going on a rampage.
響田(くつわだ)防衛大臣一派の
暴走ってことになってる
Kutsuoda just hanged himself in
his detainment cell and died.
（菊之丞）響田は さっき
留置場で首をつって死んだ
He worked for you, didn't he?!
あの人は あんたの部下だろうが！
The New Gastrea Law.
ガストレア新法
A law that will raise the social
status of the Cursed Children...
呪われた子供たちの
社会的地位を―
向上させようとする法案
But you're all for discrimination.
だが あんたは
筋金入りの差別主義者だ
You made it known that his daughter,
ヤツの娘 小比奈が
このテロにかんでることを公表し
Kohina, was involved in this act of terrorism,
and encouraged animosity
toward the Cursed Children.
呪われた子供たちに
反感を抱かせようとした
You even tried to summon a Stage Five Gastrea
ガストレア新法を止めるために―
that would destroy the Tokyo Area,
東京エリアの大絶滅を呼ぶ―
ステージⅤの召喚さえ
実行させようとした！
in order to stop the New Gastrea Law.
How could you forget?
（菊之丞）なぜ 忘れられる…
Ten years ago, those bugs killed
my wife and many others.
10年前 我が妻が
全ての人々が殺された日々を
They also took your arm and leg,
and you want me to grant the children
お前の手足と両親を奪った―
あの虫けらの血を宿した
ガキどもに―
who carry their blood human rights?
人権を与える？
They are the demons who will
bring destruction to this world.
ヤツらこそ
この世 全てを破滅させる悪魔だ
Those girls are human...
彼女たちは人間だ
I, Satomi Rentaro,
俺は… 里見蓮太郎は…
believe in Aihara Enju.
藍原延珠を信じる！
You fool...
（菊之丞）貴様というヤツは…
You saved my life...
（蓮太郎）
あんたは 俺の命を救ってくれた
If you do not want to die,
死にたくなければ
survive, Rentaro.
生きろ 蓮太郎
When I was in the pit of despair,
絶望に両目を閉じたとき
I would remember those
words and pull through.
あの言葉を思い出して
乗り切った
I have never forgotten what
happened that day ten years ago.
10年前の あの日のこと―
１日たりとも 忘れたことはない
Seitenshi-sama...
（蓮太郎）聖天子様―
I'd like to ask you something.
１つ お聞きしたいことが
What is it?
（聖天子）なんでしょう？
I saw what was inside the case.
俺は ケースの中身を見た
あ…
A broken-down tricycle.
（蓮太郎）壊れた三輪車
How the hell is that a catalyst
to summon a Scorpion?
なぜ あれが
スコーピオンを呼び出す
触媒になりえたんだ！
What are Gastrea, anyway?
そもそも ガストレアって
なんなんだ？
Please tell me, Seitenshi-sama!
教えてくれ 聖天子様！
I cannot tell you that.
それは…
お教えできません
♪～
あ… 蓮太郎ー！
Rentaro!
Oh, is your arm all better?
おお～ 手が治ったのか？
For the most part.
（蓮太郎）一応な
Did Sumire tell you the results
of my corrosion exam?
菫から 妾の
侵食率検査の結果は
聞いたのか？
ああ
Yeah. 24.9%.
24,9％だ
Oh, so it's barely changed at all.
なんだ～
ほとんど
変わってないのだな
Satomi-san...
（聖天子）里見さん…
If the hierarchy were to improve,
序列が向上すれば―
civil officer pairs would
be given special rights:
民警のペアには
特権が与えられます
A quasi-class elevation,
擬似階級の向上
and the access key to top secret information.
そして 機密情報へのアクセスキー
Satomi-san, rise through the ranks with Enju-san.
里見さん
延珠さんと
序列の階級を―
駆け上がるのです
Then you will know
そのとき
あなたは知るでしょう
the reason you were born
and who you truly are...
自分が何者で―
何をなすために
生まれてきたのかを…
～♪
Corrosion Rate
42.1%
Aihara Enju
((Medical Chart))
Percentage Until Bodily Breakdown
7.2% Remaining
#05 The Crimson Black Assassin
We've got a job.
（木更）依頼がきてるの
内容は護衛任務
It's a bodyguard request.
Rentaro, I have a bad feeling about this.
（木更）依頼がきてるの
内容は護衛任務
（延珠）蓮太郎
イヤな感じがする
Who are you?
（延珠）蓮太郎
イヤな感じがする
（蓮太郎）てめえは 誰だ
（マスター）お前の任務は何か
What is your mission?
（蓮太郎）てめえは 誰だ
（マスター）お前の任務は何か
The assassination of the Tokyo
Area representative, Seitenshi.
（ティナ）東京エリアの代表
聖天子の抹殺です